<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.ehmiiz.tech</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on blog.ehmiiz.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:56:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Solution: Automate GPO creations</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-solution-automate-gpo-creations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:56:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-solution-automate-gpo-creations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The headache of setting up recurring GPO&amp;rsquo;s I was faced with an issue not too long ago, and I spent quite some time trying to come up with an @automated solution to the problem. I thought that some hypothetical sysadmin might find themselves in a similar situation in the future, and this might save the hypothetical person some time.
The problem I was trying to solve was the following; How do we script the task of creating a new GPO with the same base settings but with different conditions (Strings (AD Groups, Hostnames), IP&amp;rsquo;s, true/false), in an automated fasion?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for Security: Generate a X-Platform Password Generator using Powershell 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-for-security-generate-a-x-platform-password-generator-using-powershell-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-for-security-generate-a-x-platform-password-generator-using-powershell-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          My history with Password Generators Password generators can be very simple and fun to build, and I thought that publishing my own history with creating them can be a good source of knowledge for other people, hence this post :)
My first version of Get-GeneratedPassword was created in Powershell 3.0, and at that point I didn&amp;rsquo;t have that many requirements, the usecase for the function was basically to stash it in my $profile to quickly set new passwords for various AD accounts.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for Security: Get Important AD Answers from this module</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-for-security-get-important-ad-answers-from-this-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 08:23:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-for-security-get-important-ad-answers-from-this-module/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Questions to AD Engineers I started to work on a new module that I call ADSEC.
Its purpose is to answer the critical AD security related questions below:
 Who can replicate secrets (password hashes) from an Active Directory domain? Who can change security permissions on the AdminSDHolder object? Who can change the membership of the Domain Admins security group? Who can reset an Active Directory privileged user account&amp;rsquo;s password? Who can disable the use of Smartcards on an Active Directory user account?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Solution: Script not digitally signed</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-solution-script-not-digitally-signed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 08:23:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/powershell-solution-script-not-digitally-signed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          “.ps1 is not digitally signed. The script will not execute on the system.” This error is clearly not really a typical error, but can be a blocker, nonetheless. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a security feature than an error.
Simple solution if you&amp;rsquo;re running this script from another service, or as an Azure Runbook, before executing the Invoke-Command:
Set-ExecutionPolicy -Scope Process -ExecutionPolicy Bypass
This will allow the powershell session process itself to bypass the Exec policy, and after termination the next powershell process has the default user or system policy.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Life 3.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-life-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 08:23:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-life-3.0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Life 3.0, Being human in the age of AI Life 3.0 by Max TegmarkFirst book on AI Personally, this was the first time reading a book about AI. And as a tech-savvy sysadmin who loves video games, sci-fi and great stories, it got me hooked.
It’s author, Max Tegmark, got me very interested in the subject and he does so by being naturally curious, super-nerdy in a fun way, and just all-round knowledgeable in tech, he’s a professor after all!
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: LOTR, The Fellowship of the Ring</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-lotr-the-fellowship-of-the-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 12:51:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-lotr-the-fellowship-of-the-ring/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          LOTR: The Fellowship of the RingOne ring to rule them all, one Ring to find them* One Ring to bring them all and in the darkness bind them Sometimes when I read books, I get a feeling to just read faster, not pay attention to detail, to get to the point of the story. While reading Lord of the rings, I forgot about that feeling completely.
I think this says a lot about Tolkien’s ability to pay attention to detail, details that forges the story deeper and deeper the more you read, it’s addictive.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Hobbit</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-the-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 12:39:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/book-review-the-hobbit/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          The Hobbit&amp;ldquo;A timeless advanture for all ages&amp;rdquo; This book was surprisingly easy to read, and it’s in my opinion light-years better than the movies. I read the entire book in Swedish, and although it’s only been a year since I read it, I already have an urge to re-read the whole book in English. The translations just don’t cut it for someone who’s interested in the lore of middle earth.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ehmiiz.tech</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Hi, and welcome to my blog I&amp;rsquo;m a 28 year old guy who&amp;rsquo;s writing this blog mostly to see how blogs can be built using github and hugo! And to remember what books I&amp;rsquo;ve read.
Goals of this blog  Simplicity Curiosity Positivity Digital bookshelf to look back on for myself Knowledge sharing Get more .md experiance  Contact You can mail me at: emil@ehmiiz.tech
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and Coming</title>
      <link>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 07:13:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ehmiiz.tech/coming/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Up &amp;amp; Coming ReviwsA list of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read starting from 2020-03-01. The books in this list will all be getting reviews in the &amp;ldquo;Posts&amp;rdquo; section of the blog sooner or later.
2020  The Hobbit Lord of the rings, fellowship of the ring Life 3.0 AI Superpowers Code: Hidden language of hard/software Weapon of math destruction AI Our final invention Headspace guide to meditation Hit refresh Lord of the rings, two towers Shell of an idea How to find a wolf in Siberia Lord of the rings, return of the king The Silmarillion  2021  Dinosaur training vol1 The Children of Húrin Beren and Luthien The fall of Gondolin Reclaim  
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>